<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://chriskcovert.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://chriskcovert.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-08-01T13:53:52+00:00</updated><id>https://chriskcovert.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">An Adventure in GitHub Pages Website Publishing</title><link href="https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/githubpages/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Adventure in GitHub Pages Website Publishing"/><published>2025-07-31T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-31T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/githubpages</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/githubpages/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>I have been working on my professional portfolio site which is can be used to compliment one’s LinkedIn profile and presence. As a project manager by profession and more broadly a technology enthusiast, I wanted to create an online presence beyond profiles on Social Media Sites like LinkedIn. A lot of job application sites that are SaaS for companies that have job openings now have more than just a place to add your LinkedIn profile address in the submission page.</p> <p>Many job application sites now give the option to include not just a LinkedIn URL</p> <ul> <li>Your personal website (the intention being your professional website)</li> <li>Github account</li> <li>Twitter account</li> <li>Instagram account</li> </ul> <p>And so I began my 1 month journey to create my own presence on the internet for my professional portfolio. That 1 month can be described as frustrating, liberating, filled with failures and triumphs.</p> <p><strong><em>First</em></strong>, I needed to decide on how to host my professional presence. I could use a free web hosting service that normally is free trial and then requires payment after the trial period is over. I did not want to pay for it if not necessary.</p> <p>I could spin up my own Virtual Private Server on a Cloud Infrastructure Service Provider and use it to host my portfolio site and various projects on the go: n8n automation, business website and file storage.</p> <p>My software development projects need version source control and I had already decided on Github.com . Well, low and behold, they have Github Pages feature which allows a person to host websites.</p> <p><strong><em>The journey:</em></strong></p> <p>I discovered Jekyll templates that are used by Github Pages to host static websites.</p> <p>I was incorrectly lead down the path of installing my on web server on my PC to develop my Jekyll based website. Development would occur locally and then using Git and Github Desktop be pushed up to GitHub.com.</p> <p>This involves a tech stack and development tools of the following:</p> <ul> <li>Windows Power-shell</li> <li>NPM</li> <li>Node.js</li> <li>Ruby on Rails (used for Ruby Gem files – needed to make the website work: whatever those are…. )</li> <li>Git</li> <li>Github Desktop</li> <li>Jekyll Template – I chose the Al-Folio template extremely popular and found in many tutorial wepages and YouTube videos.</li> <li>A JSON Linter for JSON: <a href="https://www.jsonlint.com">JSONLint.com</a></li> <li>A Mark Down linter for MD Files: markdownlint-cli</li> <li>A YAML Linter for YML/YAML Files: <a href="https://www.yamllint.com">Yamllint.com</a></li> <li>Text editor for various file editing: Sublime Text</li> <li><a href="https://www.github.com">Github.com</a> for hosting the GitHub Pages</li> <li>GitHub Actions for deployment of the site</li> </ul> <p>This is not for the feint of heart to go down this path if for you the journey is not part of the adventure on the way to your destination. I tried for 2 weeks, and probably 20 hours of time to get this website up and running just locally let alone running on Github. Had I managed to get the website running locally on my PC, it certainly would not guarantee it would work on Github where the amount of fine grained control would be even less.</p> <p><strong><em>It never happened.</em></strong></p> <p>I dove deep into tutorials and videos on how to use all of these tools on my PC to host a web server. I read and posted at the Github Al-Folio Discussion board. I searched far and wide in Reddit and Stack Overflow.</p> <p>Like how vibe coding might feel to non-coders: every time I got through 1 error, another was revealed, always eluding me.</p> <p>Then, I found the Youtube video that saved me but not without its own adventure. Apparently, you didn’t need to host first locally to design and test the Jekyll based website and then push to Github.</p> <p>All you need to do is edit the website Al-Folio repo files directly on <a href="https://www.github.com">Github</a></p> <p>The entire techstack was now</p> <ul> <li>GitHub Pages</li> <li>GitHub Actions</li> <li>I still used yamllint.com and JSONlint.com for validation</li> </ul> <p>2 major events happened before the site was up and running as it exists now:</p> <p>1.) I wasted 2 weeks working with a seller on Fiverr to fix my Al-Folio site as I could not get it up even with the reduced difficulty. It was a waste of $31 CAD, but I got my money back sort of: I have $31 CAD in credits at Fiverr. I don’t think I can get much development or help for that amount, but it is there.</p> <p>2.) Every commit to a file on the Jekyll Repo triggers a half dozen Github actions. I was doing hundreds of commits as I fumbled may way through how to properly edit the mark down files to customized the template and make it my own. I had recklessly turned on an integration between Github and my Discord Server: <a href="https://discord.com/invite/QZ2aY8dG">Project Management Achievers (North America)</a>. One Sunday afternoon after finally “getting it” I updated 15 files in about 10 minutes which triggered a hundred or more Github Actions.</p> <p><strong><em>This got my Github account permanently suspended</em></strong> for suspicious activity, I could not log into my account and the website was down.</p> <p><strong><em>The reason:</em></strong> “In particular, any repositories that use GitHub Actions solely to interact with 3rd party websites, to engage in incentivized activities, or for general computing purposes may fall afoul of the GitHub Additional Product Terms:”</p> <p>I opened a ticket with Github and begged foregiveness explaining what had happened. I was denied. I would have to start over with another GitHub account, not a huge set back, but frustrating.</p> <p>I decided to reach out to someone who works at Github on LinkedIn as going through their customer service desk was a dead end. There were 5400 people working at Github according to LinkedIn. With my wife’s help we chose 4 people from the list of 5400 people to reach out to on LinkedIn.</p> <p><strong><em>Mental Note:</em></strong> <em>This would be a great n8n Automation to build for finding who to connect with on LinkedIn if you have interest in a large company. Perhaps it already exists.</em></p> <p>I direct messaged all 4 of them with my plight. One person got back to me and said they would see what they could do. The next day I saw that my account was no longer suspended and my Github pages portfolio site was back up and running!</p> <p><strong><em>Triumph:</em></strong> <a href="https://chriskcovert.github.io">chriskcovert.github.io</a></p> <p>If you are a project manager or product manager and would like help getting a GitHub Pages website up and running for your portfolio please message me. You can choose to do the Al-Folio Jekyll template for your site, or we can be adventurous, and you can choose from one of thousands of other free or paid for Jekyll Templates.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="human-intelligence-metrics">Human Intelligence Metrics</h3> <ul class="task-list"> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Research: 1 hour</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Writing &amp; Editing: 1 hour</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Peer Review / Feedback Loop: 30 minutes</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Total Work Time: 2.5 hours</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>First Ideation: July 15, 2025</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Publication Date: July 31, 2025</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Total Elapsed Time: 16 Days</p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="professional"/><category term="social"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing a story of publishing to GitHub Pages]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A snapshot of a Technographic Service (Theirstack.com)</title><link href="https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/theirstack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A snapshot of a Technographic Service (Theirstack.com)"/><published>2025-07-19T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-19T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/theirstack</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/theirstack/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>Reading postings from HR, recruiters, and job seekers on LinkedIn for even a brief time will reveal to the reader that job placement process needs helps. There are now hundreds and thousands of applicants for a single job on LinkedIn for example. A few weeks ago I applied for a position with easy apply that had 5,288 applicants. Another example is spam emails from tech companies searching for tech customers because they have no idea who their potential customers are and blanket marketing campaigns searching far and wide.</p> <h3 id="some-of-the-questions-we-can-ask-ourselves">Some of the questions we can ask ourselves?</h3> <ul> <li> <p>How can job seekers narrow their search for jobs with their skills in industries or business verticals they would enjoy working in?</p> </li> <li> <p>Could a recruiter place a candidate at a company before the job posting was ever posted because they knew the company needed a certain skill set based on signals from the market and the company itself?</p> </li> <li> <p>How can tech, marketing, and sales departments research the trending technologies to design, build, and sell to.</p> </li> <li> <p>Their are companies that have a great product that would enhance the use of another tech product used by a potential customer, but who are they?</p> </li> <li> <p>Is there a place out there to do this research or at the very least a start-off point?</p> </li> </ul> <p>Theirstack.com is a company with the ambitious vision to store and catalog all the technologies used by all companies in the world into a technographic database. Every tech job description in the world contains valuable information that can be used for many purposes. This data is being mined from the Internet and put into one single data store to provide a valuable service to marketing, sales, recruiters, and job seekers. Theirstack is a viable service that can answer these questions.</p> <ul> <li> <p>Question: How does one even begin to find this information and then store it in a searchable way?</p> </li> <li> <p>Answer: A lot of scraping the internet of raw data and a lot of compute power running a carefully architected tech stack is needed. The global search and local data analysis to synthesize as precise and accurate a technographic database as possible is continuously improved upon using imperfect and missing information. It is expensive when scraping thousands of websites and databases daily to build the world’s largest technographic database that is both historical (for research) and timely (for decision support).</p> </li> </ul> <hr/> <p>A short primer for those not familiar with the term tech stack:</p> <p>On Monday, June 30th at 1:47 PM Eastern Time, Microsoft Co-pilot described the IT Stack or Tech Stack as: “a collection of technologies, tools, programming languages, and software products used together to develop and run applications”.</p> <h3 id="the-tech-stack-can-typically-be-broken-down-into">The tech stack can typically be broken down into</h3> <ul> <li> <p>Front-end tech (i.e. the browser, javascript)</p> </li> <li> <p>Back-end tech (i.e. server side application)</p> </li> <li> <p>Database (i.e. an SQL database)</p> </li> <li> <p>Development tools (i.e. IDE – integrated Development environment)</p> </li> </ul> <p>Knowing all the technologies a company uses to deliver their services is actionable intelligence for Sales and Marketing Departments. Knowing what the tech stack is across companies, industries, and geography overtime is a gold mine of information to the right people.</p> <p>On the one hand companies want to share enough information in their job descriptions to allow job seekers to know if they should apply. On the other and they don’t want to reveal too much information to send signals to the wrong people.</p> <p>Hence the need for Theirstack.com to scrape basically every job publicly available on the internet without any active collaboration with the job posters. It then needs to be synthesized and presented in various ways to those clever enough to know the true value of such a data store.</p> <p>Theirstack.com’s tech stack works 24/7 to provide timely and relevant data. It can be consumed by direct search on their website, APIs, and other fancy methods. The fancy methods are where the real power can be harnessed by Sales and Marketing companies across all industries and business verticals to enhance their own business efforts.</p> <p><strong>Some Metrics:</strong></p> <ul> <li> <p>5300 technologies tagged and counting</p> </li> <li> <p>50 Million job postings and counting</p> </li> <li> <p>Data from 195 countries</p> </li> </ul> <p>How their data can be used is only open to the imagination of the sales, marketing, research, competitor analysis, job seekers, and career guidance counsellors.</p> <p>You might be asking: If I am a recruiter or company posting jobs, what is the one thing is I can do to help without giving away information which doth not be given away?</p> <p><strong>Answer:</strong> Obviously adding more technologies used in the job description would be great, but we need to be realistic. If you could add a unique alpha-numeric Record ID at the very top of every job description. Especially if you post the same job to multiple sites.</p> <p>Why a record ID and why at the very top? It saves compute time and storage which lowers costs for everyone. Ask a data engineer, they will totally geek out answering the question, be patient with them.</p> <p>While looking for employment and researching product management I stumbled upon theirstack.com and i mmediately was intrigued by the value proposition of how their service might help repair a broken job search and recruiting system. I encourage any one on both sides of the job hunting table to explore the website and gain insights into the value that with a little imagination can be found there.</p> <p>This would be off – label use of their service, per their vision, this data store can be used to find customers for products and services now that their tech stack is made visible. Would having a list of every company that uses a specific ERP, CRM, CMS, or development tool be helpful?</p> <p>One fun project I am working on is using n8n.io to create an automation that pulls from Theirstack.com to find every company using n8n and posting jobs that need this skill set. This automation can be used to load these job postings into a Discord Server channel focused on the professional development of n8n.io. Shout out to Ghost Coder’s Automation Huddle Discord Server as a potential place for this to reside.</p> <p>In a world of LLM where long form answers are now considered less than 100 words and short form less than 10, I hope my first article was informative.</p> <p>This article may pop up on other social media sites to expand reach.</p> <p>I truly hope I never use AI to ghost write my articles, here are some metrics:</p> <hr/> <h3 id="human-intelligence-metrics">Human Intelligence Metrics</h3> <ul class="task-list"> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Research: 3 hours</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Writing &amp; Editing: 3 hours</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Peer Review / Feedback Loop: 30 minutes</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Total Work Time: 6 hours</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>First Ideation: June 19, 2025</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Publication Date: July 22, 2025</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Total Elapsed Time: 33 Days</p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="data"/><category term="technographic"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technical and business analysis of theirstack.com]]></summary></entry></feed>