<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://chriskcovert.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://chriskcovert.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-07-25T17:55:51+00:00</updated><id>https://chriskcovert.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">A snapshot of a Technographic Service (Theirstack.com)</title><link href="https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/theirstack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A snapshot of a Technographic Service (Theirstack.com)"/><published>2025-07-19T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-19T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/theirstack</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chriskcovert.github.io/blog/2025/theirstack/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>Reading postings from HR, recruiters, and job seekers on LinkedIn for even a brief time will reveal to the reader that job placement process needs helps. There are now hundreds and thousands of applicants for a single job on LinkedIn for example. A few weeks ago I applied for a position with easy apply that had 5,288 applicants. Another example is spam emails from tech companies searching for tech customers because they have no idea who their potential customers are and blanket marketing campaigns searching far and wide.</p> <h3 id="some-of-the-questions-we-can-ask-ourselves">Some of the questions we can ask ourselves?</h3> <ul> <li> <p>How can job seekers narrow their search for jobs with their skills in industries or business verticals they would enjoy working in?</p> </li> <li> <p>Could a recruiter place a candidate at a company before the job posting was ever posted because they knew the company needed a certain skill set based on signals from the market and the company itself?</p> </li> <li> <p>How can tech, marketing, and sales departments research the trending technologies to design, build, and sell to.</p> </li> <li> <p>Their are companies that have a great product that would enhance the use of another tech product used by a potential customer, but who are they?</p> </li> <li> <p>Is there a place out there to do this research or at the very least a start-off point?</p> </li> </ul> <p>Theirstack.com is a company with the ambitious vision to store and catalog all the technologies used by all companies in the world into a technographic database. Every tech job description in the world contains valuable information that can be used for many purposes. This data is being mined from the Internet and put into one single data store to provide a valuable service to marketing, sales, recruiters, and job seekers. Theirstack is a viable service that can answer these questions.</p> <ul> <li> <p>Question: How does one even begin to find this information and then store it in a searchable way?</p> </li> <li> <p>Answer: A lot of scraping the internet of raw data and a lot of compute power running a carefully architected tech stack is needed. The global search and local data analysis to synthesize as precise and accurate a technographic database as possible is continuously improved upon using imperfect and missing information. It is expensive when scraping thousands of websites and databases daily to build the world’s largest technographic database that is both historical (for research) and timely (for decision support).</p> </li> </ul> <hr/> <p>A short primer for those not familiar with the term tech stack:</p> <p>On Monday, June 30th at 1:47 PM Eastern Time, Microsoft Co-pilot described the IT Stack or Tech Stack as: “a collection of technologies, tools, programming languages, and software products used together to develop and run applications”.</p> <h3 id="the-tech-stack-can-typically-be-broken-down-into">The tech stack can typically be broken down into</h3> <ul> <li> <p>Front-end tech (i.e. the browser, javascript)</p> </li> <li> <p>Back-end tech (i.e. server side application)</p> </li> <li> <p>Database (i.e. an SQL database)</p> </li> <li> <p>Development tools (i.e. IDE – integrated Development environment)</p> </li> </ul> <p>Knowing all the technologies a company uses to deliver their services is actionable intelligence for Sales and Marketing Departments. Knowing what the tech stack is across companies, industries, and geography overtime is a gold mine of information to the right people.</p> <p>On the one hand companies want to share enough information in their job descriptions to allow job seekers to know if they should apply. On the other and they don’t want to reveal too much information to send signals to the wrong people.</p> <p>Hence the need for Theirstack.com to scrape basically every job publicly available on the internet without any active collaboration with the job posters. It then needs to be synthesized and presented in various ways to those clever enough to know the true value of such a data store.</p> <p>Theirstack.com’s tech stack works 24/7 to provide timely and relevant data. It can be consumed by direct search on their website, APIs, and other fancy methods. The fancy methods are where the real power can be harnessed by Sales and Marketing companies across all industries and business verticals to enhance their own business efforts.</p> <p><strong>Some Metrics:</strong></p> <ul> <li> <p>5300 technologies tagged and counting</p> </li> <li> <p>50 Million job postings and counting</p> </li> <li> <p>Data from 195 countries</p> </li> </ul> <p>How their data can be used is only open to the imagination of the sales, marketing, research, competitor analysis, job seekers, and career guidance counsellors.</p> <p>You might be asking: If I am a recruiter or company posting jobs, what is the one thing is I can do to help without giving away information which doth not be given away?</p> <p><strong>Answer:</strong> Obviously adding more technologies used in the job description would be great, but we need to be realistic. If you could add a unique alpha-numeric Record ID at the very top of every job description. Especially if you post the same job to multiple sites.</p> <p>Why a record ID and why at the very top? It saves compute time and storage which lowers costs for everyone. Ask a data engineer, they will totally geek out answering the question, be patient with them.</p> <p>While looking for employment and researching product management I stumbled upon theirstack.com and i mmediately was intrigued by the value proposition of how their service might help repair a broken job search and recruiting system. I encourage any one on both sides of the job hunting table to explore the website and gain insights into the value that with a little imagination can be found there.</p> <p>This would be off – label use of their service, per their vision, this data store can be used to find customers for products and services now that their tech stack is made visible. Would having a list of every company that uses a specific ERP, CRM, CMS, or development tool be helpful?</p> <p>One fun project I am working on is using n8n.io to create an automation that pulls from Theirstack.com to find every company using n8n and posting jobs that need this skill set. This automation can be used to load these job postings into a Discord Server channel focused on the professional development of n8n.io. Shout out to Ghost Coder’s Automation Huddle Discord Server as a potential place for this to reside.</p> <p>In a world of LLM where long form answers are now considered less than 100 words and short form less than 10, I hope my first article was informative.</p> <p>This article may pop up on other social media sites to expand reach.</p> <p>I truly hope I never use AI to ghost write my articles, here are some metrics:</p> <hr/> <h3 id="human-intelligence-metrics">Human Intelligence Metrics</h3> <ul class="task-list"> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Research: 3 hours</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Writing &amp; Editing: 3 hours</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Peer Review / Feedback Loop: 30 minutes</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Total Work Time: 6 hours</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>First Ideation: June 19, 2025</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Publication Date: July 22, 2025</p> </li> <li class="task-list-item"> <p><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Total Elapsed Time: 33 Days</p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="data"/><category term="technographic"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technical and business analysis of theirstack.com]]></summary></entry></feed>